

Marco Maida Computer scientist



www.maida.me



mmaidacs@gmail.com

About me ———

I was born in Turin, Italy, and have been tinkering with computers for as long as I can remember.

I started working professionally as a developer in 2013. After three years, I started working as game developer while studying part-time as a bachelor's student.

Once I graduated, I moved to Germany and started a joint master's and Ph.D. program. In 2022 I completed my Master's program and first-authored a research paper.

I am currently in New York, interning at Bloomberg LP.

Languages —

L'italiano è la mia lingua madre,

I am fluent in English,

und ich spreche etwas Deutsch.

Trivia —

I love camping and traveling with my bike: I often do the two together • I usually risk it, if I believe I am right . I love simplicity • I am striving not to be the smartest person in the room • I often relax by walking on a tensioned rope • I play guitar and — less successfully - sing.

Skills

I have more than **nine years of professional experience**. I extensively worked with Python, C#, C++, C, Java, Rust and Coq code. I have a mixed background of industry and academia.

I am comfortable working on complex code bases in large and small teams, and I quickly get used to new technologies. I can analyze problems and then design, implement, evaluate, document, and present my solutions.

I am outgoing and I love working in teams. Due to my game development background, I am used to collaborating with different professional figures (e.g., artists, designers, musicians) and I have an eye for user experience.

Experience

2022	R&D Intern. I worked on accelerating SAT solving using GPUs (C++, CUDA).
2019-2022	PhD Student. I studied timeliness certifications with formal verification (COQ) and on trace-based schedulability analysis on Linux (C, Rust). I mentored three interns and published three papers.
2016-2019	Game developer. I worked with Unity3D (C#) and Unreal Engine (C++) on single player and online multiplayer games shipped on Steam, PS4, XboxOne, Switch, and mobiles. I developed gameplays, AIs, dev tools and UIs.
2015-2016	Freelance Software Engineer. I built an interactive visualization software and a learning game using Unity3D (C#). I shipped on mobile devices and browsers (JS). I managed one artist I hired and collaborated with another engineer.

Education

2013-2016

2019-2022	Master in Computer Science.	Technische Universität Kaiserslautern
2016-2019	Bachelor in Computer Science.	Università degli studi di Torino
2015-2016	Game dev: Software Development	Event Horizon School.

I developed software solutions for glass processing factories. I

started as a developer (C, C++, C#, SQL) and later transitioned to

planning new features and managing a small team (\leq 5 people).

Projects and Publications

Software engineer.

2022	I created an alternative to QR Codes. Messages are encoded as unique trees. (www.maida.me/treecode)
2021	Poet - Automatic Proof Generation. I developed a tool that yields a formally verified worst-case-scenario software timing analysis. I first-authored a publication at ECRTS2022, winning its outstanding paper award. (https://drops.dagstuhl.de/opus/volltexte/2022/16336/pdf/LIPIcs-ECRTS-2022-19.pdf)
2018	Fast Mobile Cycle (FMC) Framework and Toolkit. I developed a Unity3D framework that accelerates the creation of production-ready casual games, paired by a Python toolkit to execute bulk operations on the games. (www.rithub.com/34OpenThings)

2017 Razer Chroma in Unreal Engine 4. 34BigThings I developed a framework that control LEDs on Razer's Chroma hardware. This system is used in every Chroma-compatible 34BigThings game. (www.youtube.com/watch?v=AihLBrJBufk&ab_channel=34BigThings)